There is no equal.
The Equalizer 2 is a action, thriller, crime film directed by Antoine Fuqua.
Robert McCall, who serves an unflinching justice for the exploited and oppressed, embarks on a
relentless, globe-trotting quest for vengeance when his former partner is murdered.
Robert McCall, played by Denzel Washington.
Dave York, played by Pedro Pascal.
Miles Whittaker, played by Ashton Sanders.
Sam Rubinstein, played by Orson Bean.
Brian Plummer, played by Bill Pullman.
Susan Plummer, played by Melissa Leo.
The Equalizer 2 (also promoted as The Equalizer II and EQ2) is a 2018
American vigilante action-thriller film directed by Antoine Fuqua.
It is the sequel to the 2014 film The Equalizer, which was based on the TV series of the
same name, as well as the second installment of The Equalizer trilogy.
The film stars Denzel Washington in the lead role, Pedro Pascal, Ashton Sanders,
Melissa Leo, Bill Pullman, and Orson Bean in his final film role.
It follows Marine Corps veteran and retired DIA officer Robert McCall as he
sets out on a path of revenge after an associate is murdered.
The film is the fourth collaboration between Washington and Fuqua, following Training Day (2001), The Equalizer (2014), and
The Magnificent Seven (2016), and marks the first time Washington has starred in a sequel to one of his films.
Talks of a sequel began seven months before the first film was released.
The project was officially announced in April 2015.
Filming began in September 2017 and took place in
Boston and other areas in Massachusetts.
The Equalizer 2 was released in the United States on
July 20, 2018, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received mixed reviews and was a commercial success, like
its predecessor, grossing $190 million worldwide.
Another sequel, The Equalizer 3, was released on September 1, 2023.
The film explores themes of drug dealer, martial arts, central
intelligence agency (cia), rape, kidnapping.
The tone is intense.